Guide to the Elisabeth M. Thomas, Assistant Dean of Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Elisabeth M. Thomas, assistant dean of Yale College, records
1966-1974
RU 575
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.5
(9 boxes)
The records consist of student files, schedules, bulletins, course information, and lists documenting the Yale College Dean's Office. Topics include freshman counselors, special students, student grades, and dormitories.
Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office
Thomas, Elisabeth McClure
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-B (YRG 9-B), Records of deputy, associate, and assistant deans of Yale College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of student files, schedules, bulletins, course information, and lists documenting the Yale College Dean's Office. Topics include freshman counselors, special students, student grades, and dormitories.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Deans (Education); Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale College (1887- ). Administration; Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students
- Records of Elisabeth Thomas as assistant dean, 1966-1974; Accession 1988-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2050.
  - Admissions, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admissions: Research Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Alumni Fund, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Admissions Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Coeducation Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Faculty Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Students, University, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - May Day, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minority Groups (Classes of 1968-1974), 1964-1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Risk Lists, 1969, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Safety Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 14)
  - Student Senate, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Student Steering Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Undergraduate Employment committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Wright Hall-Student Takeover, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Adviser's Packet, Class of 1975, 1971 September (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mailings to Class of 1975-September Packets, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Freshman Counselor's Packet, Class of 1975, 1971 September (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Special Student's Packet, 1971 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Freshman Packet, Class of 1975, 1971 September (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Afro-House, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Freshman Counselor Plans, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Freshman Class and Freshman Counselor Rooming Allocation, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Freshman Counselor General, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Freshman Counselor List, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Freshman Counselors
  - Freshman Counselor Salaries, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Freshman Counselor Salaries, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Administrative Data Systems, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Advisory Cornmittee Minutes (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Afro-American Studies (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence, General, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Special Students
    - Charges, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Memorandums, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Inquiries, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Students on Leave, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - List, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Rejections, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Withdrawals, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Schedules, Fall and Spring, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Selective Service, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - September Opening Days, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Sexuality, Course on Human, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Statistics (Matriculation, Withdrawals, Post-Graduate Plans, etc.), Class of 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Summer Schedules (Inter-Office), 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Teaching and Learning Committee (Faculty and Student), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Tuition Postponement Option, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Yale College Program of Study
    - Bulletin Supplement 1975, 1971 July (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Bulletin 1976, Summer, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Auditing, 1971-1972
    - Charges (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Inquiries and Rejections (Box 2)
    - Correspondence List (Box 2)
  - Yale Health Plan, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Meal Contracts Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Old Campus Business (Rooms, Correspondence, etc.), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Old Campus Publications 1976, Summer, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Memorandums to Deans and Masters, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Placement and Scheduling, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Registrar's Office, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Residential Colleges, General Information, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Room Assignments 1975, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Safety Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Secondary Schools-Class of 1975 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Alumni Fund, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Associated Student Agencies, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Yale College Undergraduate Calendar, Spring Final Examinations Schedule and Information, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Coeducation Committee-Coeducation Office, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Conferences, Student Attendance, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Bursar's Office, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972
    - Dean Moritz, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Dean Taft, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Harvard, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Dean's Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Dining Halls, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Directors of Undergraduate Studies, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Dwight Hall Advisory Board, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Faculty Meetings, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Grades, Yale College, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Correspondence
    - Personal, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Provost, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Grades, Auditors, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Wesleyan Special Students (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Special Students, 1957- (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Special Students, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Special Students, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Special Students, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Miscellaneous--Special Students, Grades and Forms, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Special Student Charges, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Special Student Schedules, Fall, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Special Students, 1966-1967
  - Special Students, 1967-1968
  - Special Students, 1968-1969
  - Special Students, 1969-1970
  - Special Students, 1970-1971
  - Campus Police Reports List (notebook), 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Campus Police Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 213 - 215)
  - Campus Police Reports, Fall, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 216 - 218)
  - Student Proposals and Records-Tutorials, Special Divisional Majors, 1969 September -October (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Executive Committee, 1964-1966 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Class of 1971 Placement Officers, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Class of 1970 Placement Officers, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Class of 1969 Placement Officers, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Class of 1973 Freshmen. and Counselors, 1969 July (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Freshmen, Class of 1972-By Counselors in College Groups (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - Freshman' List, Class of 1973 (dorm, home address, counselor, parent), 1969 October (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Freshman List-Class of 1972, 1968 October (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Class of 1973-Secondary Schools, 1969 December (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Transcript Carbons, A-Z, 1968-1971 (Box 7, Box 6, Folder 229 - 1020)
  - Alumni Fund Letter, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1021)
  - Bonds, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1022)
  - Allocation, Freshmen, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1023)
  - Bonds, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1024)
  - Calendar, Yale College, 1969 September (Box 8, Folder 1025)
  - Calendar, Yale College, 1970 September (Box 8, Folder 1026)
  - Directed Studies
    - Miscellaneous, Class of 1974, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1027)
    - Applicants, Class of 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1028)
    - Courses, Class of 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1029)
  - Early Concentration
    - Miscellaneous, Class of 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1030)
    - Miscellaneous, Class of 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1031)
    - Applicants, Class of 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1032)
    - Correspondence, Class of 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1033)
    - Instructors, Class of 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1034)
  - Faculty Advisors for Freshman, Class of 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1035)
  - Faculty Talks, Freshmen
    - Class of 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1036)
    - Class of 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1037)
    - Class of 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1038)
  - Housing
    - 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1039)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1040)
    - Freshman Annexes (Calhoun College), 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1041)
  - Gym-Physcial Fitness Test, Class of 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1042)
  - Low Testers, Class of 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1043)
  - Mailing #1
    - Class of 1973 (also: Transfers, Women, Class of 1971-1972), 1969 May (Box 8, Folder 1044)
    - Class of 1974, 1970 May (Box 8, Folder 1045)
  - Mailing #2
    - Class of 1973, 1969 July (Box 8, Folder 1046)
    - Class of 1974, 1970 June (Box 8, Folder 1047)
  - Mailing #3
    - Class of 1973, 1969 August (Box 8, Folder 1048)
    - Class of 1974, 1970 August (Box 8, Folder 1049)
  - Mailing
    - Class of 1973-September packets (Box 8, Folder 1050)
    - Class of 1974-September packets (Box 8, Folder 1051)
    - First Freshman Mailing-Class of 1975, 1971 May (Box 8, Folder 1052)
  - Parietals, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1053)
  - Placement Officers, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1054)
  - Reallocation Applications
    - Class of 1972, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 1055)
    - Class of 1973, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1056)
    - Class of 1974, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1057)
  - Spring Term Information and Schedule, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1058)
  - Spring Term Information and Schedule, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1059)
  - Vanderbilt Hall, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 1060)
  - Vanderbilt Hall, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1061)
  - Early Concentration Applicants-Class of 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1062)
  - Directed Studies Applicants
    - Class of 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1063)
    - Class of 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1064)
  - Early Concentration-Miscellaneous-Class of 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1065)
  - Directed Studies Correspondence
    - Class of 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1066)
    - Class of 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1067)
  - Directed Studies Courses-Class of 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1068)
  - Early Concentration Correspondence-Class of 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1069)
  - Directed Studies, Miscellaneous-Class of 1976, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1070)
  - Early Concentration Applicants-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1071)
  - Early Concentration Correspondence-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1072)
  - Early Concentration Grades-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1073)
  - Early Concentration Instructors-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1074)
  - Directed Studies Grades-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1075)
  - Directed Studies-Miscellaneous-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1076)
  - Class of 1972-Postgraduate Plans-Black Students (Box 9, Folder 1077)
  - Black Students: Freshman Orientation (Box 9, Folder 1078)
  - Tutoring, Early 1970's (Box 9, Folder 1079)
  - Floating Counselor Program, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1080)
  - Five-year Program Lectures, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 1081)
  - Transitional Summer Program, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 1082)
  - Freshman Allocation, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1083)
  - Miscellaneous (Filed under "Done") (Box 9, Folder 1084)
  - Freshman Counselor Program, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1085)
  - Admissions, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1086)
    - Letters Referred, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1088)
    - Ratio, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1089)
    - Rolling Decision Plan, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1090)
  - Allocation, Freshman Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1091)
  - Letter to Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1092)
  - Addresses, Freshmen-Campus-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1093)
  - Allocations, Vanderbilt Freshmen-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1094)
  - Bonds-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1095)
  - Correspondence, Freshmen-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1096)
  - Faculty Advisers for Freshmen-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1097)
  - Grades, Yale College (Fall and Spring), 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1098)
  - Health, Mononucleus Study(Infectious Mononucleosis), 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 1099)
  - Housing, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 1100)
  - Keys, Freshman-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1101)
  - Labels, Freshman Mailing-Class of 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1102)
  - Mailing #1-Class of 1975, 1971 May (Box 9, Folder 1103)
  - Mailing #2-Class of 1975, 1971 August (Box 9, Folder 1104)